CONTACT ME AT



London, SE5 0BB



eokuchukwu95@gmail.com



https://emmanuelokuchukwu.netlify.app/



https://www.linkedin.com/in/e mmanuel-okuchukwu-677011b4/

SKILLS SUMMARY

React.js

HTML5, CSS3 and SCSS

Javascript

Node.Js

Bootstrap 4

Styled-Components

Lucidchart

C#

PHP

MYSQL

MongoDB

Microsoft office 365

Good team player

Quick Learner

Excellent Written and Verbal Communication

EMMANUEL OKUCHUKWU

WEB DEVELOPER PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm an IT Professional with a keen interest in Computer Programming and Web Development. I have experience with JavaScript, I use react.js for client-side and I am currently learning node.js for server side. I have some knowledge on PHP, C#, node.Js and java. My interests however lie on full stack development using C#, SQL and javascript(node.Js and react.js), html, CSS, SCSS and styled-components.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MME IT Support Engineer

University of Queen Mary | Sept 2021 - Present

- Conduct checks on the PC and assist the lecturer during the lecture.
- I do some admin work, updating spreadsheets.
- I also contduct room checks regularly for MME(Mixed Mode education) rooms and I sort sort out tickets from our issues ticketing system.

Full-Stack Developer

Greenwich Bright G-Wizards | Dec 2017 - Sept 2018

- Initial assessment of the website to understand current problems.
- Led on-going maintenance of the web site using C#, ASP.NET.
- Designed the website user interface using CSS and HTML.
- I worked on an intutive web application that was to design for students at the univeristy of greenwich. This web app was created as a questionnaire website that will help students and their tutors communication better.

Acheivements:

I was able to lead a team of student interns with development and maintenance of the application.

I had learnt how to use git to store projects for the very first time have been using git version control since then to manage my own personal projects.

Database administrator

Light House | Sept 2017 - Dec 2017

- I was involved in the planning and development of the database.
- Database administration including installation.

CONTACT ME AT

- London, SE5 0BB
- eokuchukwu95@gmail.com
- https://emmanuelokuchukwu.netlify.app/
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/e mmanuel-okuchukwu-677011b4/

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Rockstar Social Club Clone

https://rockstar-social-club-clone-6fmypfzp2-emmanuelokuchukwu.vercel.app

The rockstar social club clone is another clone that I built with react and styled-components. The purpose of this project was to learn react hooks, axios and styled-components and to build something that I thought would be fun to build.

Amazon clone app

https://amazon-clone-build-challenge-v2.vercel.app This app was built with next.js, nextAuth and tailwindCSS. This was part of a intense five day challenge ran by ssssangha on youtube.

PatientComms Management System

https://github.com/EmmanuelOkuchukwu/pms-web-ui PCMS is a web application designed and built for the purposes of online communication between a patient and their doctor. This new system will encourage patients to be in constant communication with their clinical practitioner when they do not come in to visit their doctors. This project uses ReactJs, Java and Kotlin.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

University of Greenwich

MSc Computing and Information Systems | 2019 - 2020

- Core Modules: Software Tools and Techniques (Java), User Centered Web Engineering (PHP and MySQL) and MSc Project (React and Java).
- Grade: Merit

University of Greenwich

BSc Computing | 2014 - 2017

- Core Modules: Computer programming (Java), Information Analysis (MySQL Workbench), Application and Web Development
- Grade: 2:2

HOBBIES AND PERSONAL INTERESTS

I built a windows 10 PC.

I enjoy reading articles on technology and software engineering.

I enjoy developing web applications in my free time.

I enjoy playing Table Tennis.